彼得：令人遗憾的是，人类有一种令人震惊的冲突倾向。它的
Peter: It's a sad fact that human beings have a shocking propensity for conflict. It’s
据估计，在上个世纪，有230万人在战争中死亡，其中大多数人死亡
estimated in the last century, 230 something million people were killed in war and most
他们是非战斗人员。许多富裕国家现在正在努力推动机器人技术的发展
of them were non-combatants. Many rich countries now are pushing really hard into robotic technology
减少士兵的伤亡率，并开发所谓的智能武器，这将减少
to reduce soldier casualty rates, and developing so called smart weapons, which will reduce
非战斗人员的死亡。所以，现在，这些机器人并非完全自主。那里
the deaths of non-combatants. So, right now, these robots are not fully autonomous. There
是一个人类负责实际射击武器并造成伤害或死亡
is a human being responsible for actually firing the weapon and causing harm or death
对另一个人。但是，接受这种人类的压力似乎越来越大
to another human being. But there seems to be a growing pressure to take that human being
离开发射循环，并实际让机器人做出是否自主决定
out of the firing loop, and to actually have robots making autonomous decisions about whether
他们杀人还是不杀人。那么，伦理学对这种情况有什么看法呢？
they kill human beings or not. So, what is ethics have to say about this situation?
道格：我认为道德机构这个词在这里很重要。道德机构是什么，是那个机器人
Doug: I think the term moral agency is important here. What moral agency is, is does that robot
或者那个人有能力做出是对还是错的决定。
or that individual have the capacity to make a decision whether it's right or wrong.
彼得：好的，但是人类正在努力解决这个问题。那么，我们怎么能期望机器能够做到这一点？
Peter: Okay but human beings struggle with this. So, how would we expect the machine to be able to do that?
道格：嗯，可能，他们没有。他们现在还没有。那么，没有道德代理，那么
Doug: Well, probably, they don't. They don't at this point. So, without moral agency, then
在这种情况下，道德不适用于机器。所以，这台机器既不道德也不道德。
ethics isn't applied in this context against the machine. So, the machine is neither ethical nor unethical.
彼得：因为它说不出是非？
Peter: Because it cannot tell right from wrong?
道格：它没有道德代理，但这意味着，如果那是机器
Doug: It has no moral agency but what that means though is that if that's the machine
没有道德代理，那么我们回到运行或编程机器的人。
without moral agency, then we come back to the person running or programming the machine.
他们对这个道德机构负有责任。所以，它只是回落。所以个人，
They become liable for that moral agency. So, it just falls back. And so that individual,
那些工程师或机器人设计师是有道德责任的人。
those engineers or that robot designer is the one that has the ethical responsibility.
彼得：好的，因为他们创造的机器，没有这个......
Peter: Okay because of the machine that they have created, does not have this…
道格：没有道德机构，没错。
Doug: There's not have moral agency, correct.
彼得：......责任在于创造或部署它的人。
Peter: …the responsibility is back on the person who either created it or deployed it.
道格：是的。我刚刚在此发现了很多文献。他们是机器人道德
Doug: Yes. There's quite a literature I just discovered on this. They are robot ethics
和机器伦理......在这方面有相当多的争论回到这一点
and machine ethics… there's quite a bit out there on this that debates this back and
如你所知。我们已经谈过这个了。那么，对我来说，就是这样
forth as you well know. We've talked about this a little bit. So, for me, that is the
定义构造。这是道德机构。
defining construct. It's moral agency.
彼得：我知道这是一个主题，在机器人社区，我们谈论它。
Peter: I know it's a topic that in the robotics community, we talk a little bit about it.
我认为我们几乎没有谈到这个问题，但这才是真正的问题
I don't think we talked about it nearly enough but this is the one that really seems to get
人们兴奋或愤怒，这是机器人在战争中的想法。它已经开始引起了
people excited or angry, is this idea of robots in warfare. It already starting to cause a
很多争论。
lot of contention.
道格：这并不让我感到惊讶。当然，好莱坞刚刚创造了奇迹，
Doug: That doesn't surprise me. And Hollywood, of course, has just done wonders with that,
随着阿诺德施瓦辛格系列，机器人占领了世界。它已经
with the Arnold Schwarzenegger series, with the robots taking over the world. It's been
多年来的共同主题。
a common theme for ages.
彼得：当然。这是所有机器人电影中反复出现的主题。
Peter: Absolutely. It's the recurring theme in all robot movies.
道格：是的。在这里，我们刚刚讨论过Asimov，IsaacAsimov和他1942年的短篇小说。
Doug: Yes. Here, we've just discussed beforehand Asimov, Isaac Asimov and his 1942 short story.
短篇小说叫做Runaround。
The short story is called Runaround.
彼得：当然。这带来了他着名的机器人角色，是吗？
Peter: Absolutely. This brings in his famous roles of robotics, yes?
道格：没错。我要读它们吗？
Doug: Exactly. Shall I read them?
彼得：是的。
Peter: Yes.
我最近发现了这个。所以，他有四条法律。刚刚增加了一项新法律。
I discovered just this recently. So, he's got four laws. A new law was just added.
彼得：第零法则。
Peter: The zeroth law.
道格：是的。根据这些，所有机器人都应该了解所有情况并遵守
Doug: Yes. According to these, all robots should understand all circumstances and obey
这些法律。1.机器人不得伤害人类，或
these laws. 1. A robot may not injure a human being, or
通过无所作为，让人类受到伤害。
through inaction, allow a human being to be harmed.
2.机器人必须服从人类收到的命令，除非此类命令发生冲突
2. A robot must obey orders it receives from human beings, except when such orders conflict
有了这个第一定律。是的，那个人很伤心。
with this first law. Yes, that one's harming.
3.只要这种保护不冲突，机器人就必须保护自己的存在
3. A robot must protect its own existence as long as such protection does not conflict
与第一或第二法律。换句话说，伤害人类。还有另一个
with the first or second law. In other words, harming humans. There's another
一。阿西莫夫补充说。没有机器人可能会危害人类或通过
one. Asimov added the fourth. 4. No robot may harm humanity, or through
不作为，让人类受到伤害。因此，这为一些机器设定了基础
inaction, allow humanity to come to harm. So, this sets the basis for some of the machine
道德讨论，这很有趣，但我回到道德机构。
ethics discussion, which is fascinating but I go back to moral agency.
彼得：那么，如果一台机器在其控制计算机中编码了这些规则，那就是那个机器人
Peter: So, if a machine had these rules encoded in its control computer, would that robot
有道德代理？
have moral agency?
道格：如果可以做出那个决定，是的。
Doug: If it could make that decision, yes.
彼得：好的。
Peter: Okay.
道格：是的，好的一点。它会。那时，我们就有道德或不道德的行为。
Doug: Yes, good point. It would. And at that point, then we have ethical or unethical behavior.
彼得：今天的机器人目前缺乏的是能够制造......的第一个机器人
Peter: What robots today currently lack is the ability to be able to make… first of
所有，充分了解世界上正在发生的事情，但我认为也应该理解
all, sufficiently well understand what's going on in the world but I think also, to understand
他们行动的后果，预测未来。'如果我这样做，那么它
the consequences of their actions, to predict into the future. ‘If I did this, then it
会对人类造成伤害或伤害。
would cause harm or injury to a human being’.
道格：是的。
Doug: Yes.
彼得：我们距机器人技术还有很长的路要走。我们需要那种
Peter: We're a long, long way off that in robotics. We would need to have that kind
为了实现像机器人这些法则这样的能力。
of capability in order to implement something like these laws of robotics.
道格：当然，是的。让我感到惊讶的是，彼得和你们所有人的速度有多快
Doug: Absolutely, yes. What surprises me is how fast we’ve come Peter, and you of all
人们会知道这一点。你们在机器人技术方面的速度是惊人的。
people would know that. The speed of what you guys are doing in terms of robotics is staggering.
彼得：我们走了很长的路，但我认为我们还有很长的路要走。我认为
Peter: We have come a long way but I think we have got an awfully long way to go. I think
就感知世界状况而言，我们在那里做了很多工作。在
just in terms of perceiving the state of world we’ve got a lot of work to do there. In
为了弄清楚我们的行为的后果，机器人，是的，我认为这是一个
order to figure out the consequences of our actions, robotically, yes I think that's a
那里还有大量的工作要做。
huge body of work yet to be done there.
道格：是的。是的我同意。
Doug: Yes. Yes, I agree.